We're going to now talk about how an image is represented in the computer,
我们将要讨论如何在计算机中表示图像
how a color image is represented in the computer,
如何在计算机中表示彩色图像
and how a video is represented in the
以及如何在计算机中表示视频
and the very important concepts of sampling, and representation, and
还有很重要的采样、表示和量化的概念
quantization. It's always very good to have in mind the
我们非常容易地就可以想到
images that we normally take with our cameras.
我们一般通过照相机拍摄的图像
But please remember, while we see here and we talk a few videos ago that images
但是请记住 我们在这里看到的和我们之前视频中提到的
that we are familiar with is just a very small part of the spectrum of images that
我们所熟悉的图像仅仅是 我们能够在电磁波谱上
we can acquire at different wavelengths and with different modalities.
在不同的波长、以不同的方式所获取的图像的非常小的一部分
And the concept of something in quantization are relevant for basically
量化的概念在一定程度上是和那些方式相关的
all of those modalities, we always going to have to sample, we are always going to
我们总是要进行采样 我们总要进行量化
quantize. But again, it's good to have in mind when
但再提一次 最好在脑海中留着这个念头
we talk about these different ideas, how they apply to the images that we are most
当我们谈论这些不同的想法时 要如何将这些想法
familiar with, which are the images from our own digital cameras.
应用到我们最为熟悉的由数码相机所拍摄的图片上
So, the basic idea is as follows. We may say half light, basic error
所以 基本思路是这样的
reflecting on the objects, and the light that is reflected on the
光线被物体反射 并进入照相机
objects goes into the camera. And, what we have are sensors in the
同时 在照相机里面我们有传感器
camera as we can see here. Remember, in our eyes, we have the retina
如同在这里看到的那样 记住 在我们的眼睛里有视网膜
and the retina have the cones and rods, those were the sensors.
视网膜上有视锥细胞和视杆细胞 那些就是传感器
In digital cameras, we have sensors, exactly the same way as we have sensors
在数码相机中 我们有传感器 它们的功能和我们眼睛里的传感器是一样的
in our eyes. So, this is just one example of a sensor.
所以 这仅仅是一个传感器的例子
The energy is coming in, there are filters,
能量进来后 有滤波器
and then basically, the energy is acquired and is transmitted.
然后 这些能量被接受和传输
So, the energy is sent and transmitted. And normally, what we are going to have
因此 能量被感知然后被传输 通常 在一个普通的相机里
on a regular camera is the two-dimensional array of these sensors.
我们有一个二维的传感器矩阵
So, each one of these is going to be one of these.
这里的每一个都是一个传感器
Okay? And normally, they are arranged in a
通常 正如我们看到的
square or rectangular fashion as we see it here.
它们以正方形或长发形的形式排列
So, we have actually kind of a discrete number that's when we go and buy each of
因此 我们实际上得到了离散值 当我们去购买相机时
the cameras, we hear that this is about 1,000 x 1,000.
我们会听到这是 1,000 x 1,000
It means, we're actually going to talk a bit more about that in a second.
我们要多谈一会儿这个
It means that we have 1,000 sensors in this direction,
这意味着 我们在这个方向上有1,000个传感器
1,000 sensors in this direction, so a total of a thousand square sensors.
这个方向上也有1,000个传感器 共有1,000的平方这么多个传感器
So, once again, light is reflecting objects, is projected into the camera,
所以 再次说明 物体反射的光投射进照相机
and is sensed by the camera, but all the process has a step of
并被相机所感知 但所有的过程都要经过离散化这一步
discretization. Some of you might be more familiar than
你们中的一些人可能比其他人更熟悉离散化
others with this. Those of you that took classes in, in
上过数字信号处理这门课的同学
digital signal processing and are aware of A to D converters. This would be very
已经了解了模数转换器 (AD converter)  这部分对你们而言会
simple and very familiar to you, but let's just review it for those that
非常简单而熟悉 但让我们为了那些不熟悉这些概念的同学
are not so familiar with the concepts. So, we see here the light represented
复习一下这些 所以 我们可以看到这儿发出光
here, is reflected from the object and it goes into the sensing device.
光线由物体反射 并进入到传感器件之中
Think about your digital cameras. So this is a blown-up of what we have
想想你的数码相机 因此 这是后面这个成像的放大
back here. It looks, the object is continuous space,
它看起来 这个物体在空间中是连续的
everything is continuous, but we actually get a discrete representation of that
任何物体都是连续的 但我们实际上得到的是
object and the discretization applies in two different directions.
离散化表示的物体 而离散化被用在了两个不同方面
One is a spatial discretization. So we have a discrete number of sensors
一个是空间离散化 这儿我们的传感器数量是离散的
here, and basically the light. One of the simplest modes is that we
注意这个光 最简单的一种模式就是
integrate, each one of these integrates the light arriving to it,
做积分 这里的每个传感器累积其接收到的光线
so that's a discretization in the space. There's also discretization in the
所以空间上是离散化的 而在幅值上也是离散的
amplitude. We're not going to be able to capture
我们无法捕获
every single level of gray, every single level that is reflected from the object,
由物体反射而来的光的每一个层级的灰度
but we're going to have to discretize it as well.
但我们仍要将其离散化
So let's see. Let's talk a bit more about that.
所以 让我们来看一看 关于这个问题让我们多谈一点
This is the object as we actually see it. And let, let's just look at one line.
这是我们真实看到的物体 让我们先来看一条线
I cross this object. So, we see that there it has different
我划过这个对象 因此 我们可以看到不同的值
values, it goes from white to gray. So let's just now draw the profile which
从白色到灰色 因此 让我们把这里看到的情况描绘出来
is what we see here. So it's very light, white, and then it
这里非常亮 是白色
becomes a bit dark, and if we see here, let me just erase this so we can
接着变暗了一点 如果我们看这儿 让我抹去这个以便
basically see it more clearly. If we go around,
我们能够看得更清楚 如果我们移动一下
I'm going to just mark it here. If we're going around, we see that it's
让我在这儿做个标记 如果我们移动一下
going for white then it's dark, then it just becomes brighter a bit, and
会看到它将是白色 然后变暗 接着它变得亮了一点儿
goes down again, and then it's white again.
然后再次变暗 最后它又变成白色
So it has kind of these profile. High is white, then it go dark, and then
所以它的形状是这个样子 高的表示白色 接着变暗
it goes up, down, and then it becomes white again.
然后它上升 下降 接着它又变成白色了
Of course, it's not perfect. It has some noise.
当然 它并不完美 它含有一些噪声
Even when we go and buy paint and paint a wall, basically, we think that it's
就像当我们购买涂料并粉刷了一面墙时
exactly the same color. But it's actually not.
我们认为粉刷过的墙成了一个颜色 但实际上它不是
It has some small variations, which are represented here.
它有一些小的变动 比如这儿
So again, there are two processes happening here.
再次重申 这里用到了两种处理过程
One is sampling. We are going to basically look at the
一个是采样 我们要根据一定的离散间隔来取值
values at certain discrete intervals. We are not going to have the values all
我们不会取遍所有的值
around. We are going to have it at certain
我们只在一定间隔上取值
intervals. Okay?
明白了吗？
That's one discretization. The second discretization is, we're not
这是一个离散化过程 第二个离散化过程就是
going to be able to represent every single possible value here.
我们不能把这里的每一个值都表示出来
We're going to basically just represent a few of them.
我们将只会表示它们中的某些值
We're going to round them. So let's just give an example.
我们将要近似地表示它们 所以让我来举一个例子
A very simple illustration on how can we round?
一个非常简单的例子 来说明我们如何近似
Let's say that we see the value, 17.5. So basically we see that this is the
比方说 我们来看这个值 17.5 所以基本上我们看到
value that is representing a particular gray value here.
这个值表示这里的一个特定的灰度值
So how can we round this? One way is just to truncate it like this.
那么我们如何来近似这个呢？ 一种方法是像这样对它进行截取
And then basically say, you know, I know that what came into the sensor is 17.5,
然后就是 我知道进入传感器的值是17.5
but actually I'm going to represent it by 17." Okay?
但实际上我用17来表示它
So, there are more ways of doing this and we are going to talk in more detail about
还有许多方法来做近似 我们就通过量化的例子再详细讨论
quantization. This is simply this conversation in this
这是采样 在这个方向上
direction of the great value is called quantitation.
灰度值的离散化被称为量化
We could also consider, for example, if we had 17.5 as before, we could actually
我们还可以考虑 例如如果我们和以前一样还取17.5
divide it by 2. Take this and multiply by 2.
我们可以把它除以2 在此基础上并乘以2
So basically we divided by 2, then we round, and then we multiply by 2.
也就是我们除以2 然后我们近似取整 接着我们乘以2
And I'm just going to ask you, as a very simple exercise, what's this value?
那么我要问你的是 作为一个小练习 这里得到的值是多少？
And what will happen if you're still dividing by 2,
如果 再除以2 会发生什么呢？
we basically for example, divide by 4. Round down, and then multiply by 4.
我们举例来说 把它除以4  向下近似取整 然后再乘以4
And I'm going to have you think about this, as a simple aromatic operation,
好好想一想这个 这是一个简单的算术运算
we're going to discuss a lot about this particular operation in the chapter on
我们将在量化这一章就这个特别的运算进行更多的讨论
quantization. But to recap, we have two ways of
那么总结来说 我们有两种方式进行采样
sampling. One is the, two ways to get ways of
一个是 其实是两种使用了离散化的方法
discretization. One is sampling in the spatial domain,
一种就是空间域的采样
and the other is quanitization in the gray values.
另一种就是灰度值的量化
So, the basic idea is that while we have started from a continuous object that
因此 其基本思想是 当我们从一个连续的对象开始
basically lives in the whole space and has multiple gray values,
它在空间上是连续的 同时有各种各样的灰度值
we end up with a discrete object that has discrete, discretization both in the
通过对空间域和灰度值进行离散化
spatial domain and also in the gray values.
我们最终得到了一个离散化的物体
The whole idea of good digital cameras is to have a dense enough sampling here,
好的数码相机 就是在这里有足够密集的采样
and very, very fine level of quantization, so we don't notice that
还有非常精细的量化 以致于我们都不会发现
everything is discrete. But it's actually, it is discrete.
这一切都是离散的 但实际上 它们是离散的
So we have pixel values, each one of these is called a pixel.
因此 我们得到了像素值 其中每一个被称为一个像素
This comes from picture, element,
这来自于图像元素
and is denote as pixel. And actually I'm going to just, if you
并用像素来表示 实际上
want to Google or you want to search on the web a bit,
如果你用谷歌或者在网上搜索一下
I'm going to just, you might find it entertaining to find out who basically
你会发现有趣的事
was the first person to use the term pixel.
你将发现第一个使用像素这个词的人
It's actually a very famous statistician and you can have fun looking for that on
他实际上是一位非常著名的统计学家
the internet or discuss about that on in the blogs when you find out about that.
你会从在互联网上搜寻答案中找到乐趣 还可以在博客讨论你的发现
So, everyone of these is discrete, both in space and is discrete also in its
因此 这些都是离散的 在空间上和灰度值上都是如此
grey values. And that's how we get pixels.
我们就是这样得到像素的
And once again, the more we have of this and the more we have of the levels, the
再次强调 采样的密度越高 量化的层级越密
better the image it is. So, regular images will be, for example,
图像的质量就越好 因此 就一般的图像而言
256 x 256 spatial domain. That will means that it will have 256
例如 256×256 在空间域中 这将意味着
square pixels and maybe it's represented by 8 bits.
将有256的平方这么多的像素 也许每个像素由8个比特位 (bit) 表示
So every pixel, is represented by 8 bits, which means that it can have, it's can
因此 每一个像素用 8 bits 表示 这意味着它可以
represent 256 different gray values and we are going to see how important this
表示256个不同的灰度值 我们将看到这个的重要性
is. Both the spatial discretization and the
空间的离散化以及
quantization of gray values are extremely important.
灰度值的量化 都是相当重要的
We can have better images, for, let me just go back.
我们还能够获得更好的图像 那么 让我们回到前面
We're going to have, for example, we might have an image that has, instead of
比如说 有一张图像 这里不是256×256
256 x 256, it might have 512 x 512 and still 256 letters.
而是512×512 并且仍然是 256个灰度值
So it's going to take more memory to save that image, but it's going to have a
这样这张图像需要更多存储空间 但它将拥有更好的质量
better quality. And once again, when you're buying
那么重复一遍 当你要购买数码相机时
digital cameras, they normally tell you a lot about this number,
他们通常会对你重点强调这个数字
how many pixels it has, and that tells you how fine the sampling
即 有多少像素 它可以告诉你采样的密集程度
is. We want a lot of pixels,
我们想要许多的像素
so they are so close to each other, that we, that we can actually believe that
因此它们是如此地紧挨在一起 以至于我们实际上相信
it's a continuous domain and the same at the level of the grey values.
它是一个连续的空间 同理 也相信灰度值的层级也是连续的
So, once again, one, each one of these is a pixel and it's represented by gray
因此 再次说明 这些中的每一个都是一个像素 它们由灰度值表示
values. Now this is a black and white image.
现在这是一幅黑白图像
We actually, in our cameras, we have color images.
实际上 在我们的相机里 我们得到的是彩色图像
Color images are represented by three of these images.
彩色图像是由这样的三个图像来表示
One for red, one for green,
一个红色 一个绿色
and one for blue. So basically the cameras acquire, I'm
还有一个蓝色 所以基本上来讲 照相机获取的图像
going to explain a bit more about that in a second, acquire three images.
我将在这里多讲解一下这个问题 获取三幅图像
One represents the blue colors, how much blue there is in the scene,
一张显示蓝色 代表场景中有多少蓝色
the other represents the green, and the other represents the red.
另一张显示绿色 还有一张显示红色
And this is called red, green, and blue,
这就是所谓的红色、绿色和蓝色 (RGB)
so you often going to hear images which are R, G, and B.
所以你经常会听到 RGB图像
I should make one comment about this. Most low-end to mid-end consumer cameras,
关于这点我再说明一下 大部分的低端和中端消费级相机
they actually don't really capture full two-dimensional rays for each one of the
其实它们都没有真正地捕获每种颜色的完全的二维矩阵
colors. So we would like to have each one red,
我们想要的是单独的红色
green and blue. So that's what we would like to have red,
绿色和蓝色图像 因此我们将有红色
green, and blue.
绿以及蓝
That would be the ideal scenario and the more expensive cameras actually do that,
这将是理想的情形 更昂贵的相机真正做到了这一点
basically they capture three full images. Most consumer cameras, if you buy a
它们捕获了三个完整的图像 而大多数消费级相机 如果你买了一款
low-end digital camera, actually does something slightly different, something
低端数码相机 实际上有些东西稍许不同
that is called mosaic. And the basic idea is that it capture the
会出现被称为马赛克的东西 简单地说
pixels with interleaving in the colors, will capture out a red, a green, a red, a
就是它以颜色交错的方式捕获像素 它捕获了一个红色 一个绿色 一个红色
green, and so on. And here, it will capture a red here, a blue,
一个绿色等等 这里将捕获一个红色 一个蓝色
blue, red, and so on.
一个蓝色 一个红色 等等
So the next one will be red, green, red, green.
所以下一个会是红色 绿色 红色 绿色
The next one will be blue, red, blue, red.
下一个又是蓝色 红色 蓝色 红色
So actually, it's not having the triple the amount of pixels, is actually having
因此 实际上 它不具有三倍的像素量
one pixel red, one green, one red, one green.
其实是 一个红色像素 一个绿色 一个红色 一个绿色
From this, we are going to have to interpolate and that we're going to learn
由此看来 我们需要进行插值
how to do those things in the 3rd and 4th week weeks in this class.
我们将学习如何插值 这会在第三和第四周的课程中讲到
We're going to have to go, because to represent a full color image at every
因为要显示出全色彩图像
pixel, we're going to have to go red, green and blue.
就需要每个像素中 都有红色 绿色和蓝色 (RGB)
So, we do have the red, we're going have to create, somehow the green and blue,
这里 我们已经有了红色 我们还要补充绿色和蓝色
and that's down from the neighboring pixels.
这是通过临近像素的信息来得到的
Here, we have the green, we are going to have to create the red and the blue.
这儿 我们有绿色 我们将要补充上红色和蓝色
So, we are going to have to complete the three channels to be able to see a color
因此 我们将要补充完成三个颜色通道 以便看到一幅彩色图像
image. When you buy a digital cameras, they
你购买一台数码相机时
actually normally tell you the size on this which is the size after it have done
他们通常告诉你一个尺寸 这个尺寸是插值后的结果
that population, although, they as they as they say the regular consumer images
然而 他们会说 一般的日常照片 获取的图像就是这样
capture this. So they actually capture 1/3 of the data
其实 相机实际捕获的数据
that they tell you that they're giving to you,
仅有他们告诉你的那个数值的三分之一
that the data they tell you they're giving to you has been interpolated from
因为给你的是对拍摄的图像进行插值后 得到的图像
what has been captured. So we have discrete images.
所以这里我们得到了一些离散的图片
We have a red, green, and blue channels. We're going to think about them as red,
我们有红色 绿色和蓝色的通道 我们将它们想成
green, and blue so we already went from this representation to the interpolated,
红色 绿色和蓝色 这时我们已经对得到的图像进行了插值
by the way this is called mosaic. So that's how color images are created.
顺便说一下 这叫做马赛克 彩色图像就是这样制作出来的
Now, how are videos? So this is how you have a color in your,
那么 对于视频来说是怎样的呢？你已经知道了
an image in your computer. You have three channels, three arrays of
彩色图像是如何保存在电脑中的 有三个通道 三个二维离散数组
two dimensional discrete values, one for red, one for green, one for blue.
分别对应红色 绿色和蓝色
So what happened with videos? Videos basically repeat this.
对于视频来说是怎样的呢 基本来说视频和这很类似
So one image has, red, green, and blue.
这里一张图片含有红色 绿色 蓝色 (RGB)
And what happen in video, you have multiple of these.
在视频中 你会有很多这些图像
For example, for one second of video, in, in some of the formats you're going to
比如 在视频的一秒钟内 一些格式下
have 30 of these. So you're going to have 30 x RGB and each
你将会获得30张图片 也就是说 你将会得到30张 RGB 图片
one of these, remember, is one of these two-dimension structures.
然后每一张图片 还记得吗 都是二维结构
So basically, if you are having, if you want to have one second of video in your
基本来说 如果你想在你的电脑里保存一秒的视频
computer, you'll have 30 * 3 images. 30 images in 1 second and 3 because you
你会得到 30*3 张图片 1秒钟内有 30张图片
have three colors. So in 1 second, you're going to have 90
乘以3 是因为有三种颜色 所以在1秒钟内
images of this type to represent 1 second of video.
将有90张这种类型的图片来表示 1秒钟的视频
And, of course, 90 images, so let's say 90 images at the resolution of 512 x 512,
当然 90张图片 我们来看看90张分辨率为 512 x 512 的图片
each an 8 bits each. So this is what you need to represent at
每个像素 占 8 bits 这就是你需要在这个相对低的分辨率情况下
relatively very low resolution. This is not very high resolution, this is
所占用的存储空间 这不是特别高的分辨率
pretty standard, but basically this is what your going to need to represent 1
这很标准 但是这就是你电脑展示 1秒视频需要的东西
second of a video in your computer. By the way, it's just saying that it's 3
顺便提一下 这里的 3*8 bits
* 8 bits, three times because we have [INAUDIBLE] bits.
乘以3 是因为我们有 RGB 三个通道
Sometimes people will say that our resolution is 24 bits,
有时候人们会说分辨率是 24 bits
so we use 24 bits to represent basically a pixel.
那是指我们使用 24 bits 来表示一个像素
Okay? So this is how you have.
这就是你使用的方法
If you go now to a computer that knows how to deal a program that knows how to
如果你有一台电脑 上面有程序知道如何处理图片
deal with images you're going to see basically two-dimensional discrete arrays
你会看到很多二维离散数组
as many as seconds or frames you have in your image.
和你图片包含的秒数或帧一样多
It's one of these 30, it's called a frame, and you have 30 of this in a
这是三十分之一 我们称它为一帧 一秒钟内有30帧
second or 30 images. When we talk about still images, with we
或30张图片 当我们说到静止图像的时候
talk normally about images, when we talk about videos, each one of these we call
也就是我们通常说的图片 当说到视频的时候 这里每一张图片
it a frame. So this is how your images are
我们称之为帧 所以这就是你的图像的表现方式
represented. Let's just look a bit more about how
我们再来看看
important and what are the effects of your resolution in space, on your
在空间尺度中的分辨率、灰度值的分辨率的效果和重要性
resolution in gray values. Meaning, how many pixels you're going to
也就是说 这里有多少像素
have and what are the gray values that you're going to use for them.
以及你会为它们设置数值为多少的灰度值
So, this is again the same type of representation.
这里又是相同类型的表示
This is how 1 color of 1 image, or 1 color of 1 frame is represented.
这就是一张单色的图片 或者一张单色帧所呈现的方式
If you have the letter D, then these pixels are 0.
如果你有一个字母D 这些像素是 0
When we have 8 bits, normally 0 is black and 1 or 256, 255,
当我们有 8 bits 时 一般来说 0代表黑色
actually is white. So if you are going with 8 bits, you can
1 或者 255 表示白色 所以如果是 8 bits
go from 0 to 255. 0 is black, 255 is white.
你可以使用从 0到255 这些数值 0表示黑色 255表示白色
Sometimes at 255 is called 1 if you want to talk about the interval between 0 and
有时候255 也可以称作1 如果你想使用 0和1之间的间隔表示
1. So, although, you see this,
所以 虽然你看到的是这样
actually the computer is represented by a bunch of 0 for the black region.
其实在计算机中 是由很多0 表示黑色的区域
Then, let' say that this region is in the middle of the gray value,
这部分区域的像素值是处于灰度值中间的位置
it would be an equivalent of a 128 value or a 0.5 value.
它们的灰度值可能等于 128 或者等于0.5
So we see here 0.5 and then 1 for basically the white.
我们看这里灰度值是0.5 白色用 1 表示
So this is your discrete representation of this image in the computer.
这就是你的电脑中对这幅图的离散表示
Okay? At every pixel, you have a discrete
对于每一个像素 都有一个离散值
value. Now, sometimes, one of the things that
有时
happen is because you have only 256 different levels that you can use.
你能用的只有 256 个不同的等级
Sometimes your image is too bright and you might not be able to represent the
有时候你的图片太亮 你也许无法表现
small variations in brightness, there. Remember, the human visual system can
亮度之间微小的不同 请注意 人类视觉系统可以
basically adapt to multiple level, multiple levels of brightness, but not
适应许多的等级 很多的亮度等级
all of them at the same time. The same for an image.
但是并不是同时适应所有等级的亮度 对图片来说也是一样
We can capture many, many levels, maybe 256,
我们可以获得很多很多等级 也许256个
but if we have to deal with a very dark region and a very light region at the
但是 如果我们希望同时处理这样一个有暗区域和明亮区域的图片的时候
same time, we are in trouble. And sometimes, the very small variations
我们就有了问题 有时候 我们不能获取到
in this light region, we're not going to be able to capture and that's called
在明亮区域内很小的差别 这被称作 饱和度
saturation. So, it's going to look all white because
所以这里看起来全白因为
it all got to the 255, maybe it was above 255.
这里所有像素值都达到了255 也许超过255
We want it to be above 50, 255 because it was very bright.
超过了255 因为那里特别亮
So that happens very often, we take images and sometimes we see
这经常发生 我们拍照后 有时我们看到
what's called specularities or, or very strong reflections and it looks white,
被称作高光的部分 或者很强的反射 使其看起来为白色
it looks very, very light and that's because the image, the sensor has
它看起来十分明亮 那是因为 图片 传感器已经饱和了
saturated. So, this explains, now you know why, why
所以 这就是原因 现在你知道为什么这会发生了
that is happening. You have a discrete amount of levels, a
你有一些离散的等级
discrete amount of values to represent your image,
一些离散的数值 来表现你的图片
and this went above and beyond what you can represent with that discrete amount
这里的值超过了你可以表示的离散值的范围
of values. So again, two discretizations, one in
所以再次重申 两个离散化过程
space and one in gray values. And look what happened, what's the
一个是空间尺度上的 一个是灰度值尺度上的 来看看发生了什么
effect? And you know that, because if you have a
有什么样的效果 其实你知道的 因为如果你有
digital camera or if you see images on the, on the web, on the Internet, you see
一台数码相机 或者如果你在网络上浏览图片
images have different resolution. So if you were to use a lot of pixels,
你会看到不同分辨率的图片 所以如果你使用了大量的像素
you might see this. So this means that you have something
你可能会看到类似这样的图片 也就是说
which is very, very fine, a lot of pixels and that looks really
你有一张非常非常精细的图 很多的像素 看起来很棒
nice. On the other hand, if you have something
另一方面 如果你的图像很粗糙
which is much more coarse, less dense, so you have less pixels, you're going to see
没那么稠密 意味着没有那么多像素 你会看到像这样的图片
something like this. And it's very clear to see, for example,
显而易见 比如说
how you know, this line is very nicely represented here is not so nicely
这条线显示得很清晰 而这里就有些模糊
represented here. You can see very easily this small
你可以很容易地看到这里的小数字
numbers here, not so easy here. You look at these numbers here, they're
但这里却不那么容易 看看这里的数字
not so clear here. So here we only have changed the spatial
它们在这里就没那么清晰 这里我们只是改变了空间分辨率
resolution. We have not changed the number of gray
我们没有修改灰度值
values. Still, let's say we have 256.
我们仍然有 256个值
So each one of these is represented with 256 and each one of these is represented
所以这里每一个像素都可由 256个灰度值表示 这里也是这样
of 256, but we are not able, basically, to represent so fine detail with this as
但是我们在低分辨率下无法像高分辨率中表现那么高的精细度
we are with this. And you can think about, once again, if I
你可以想一想 再一次
want to draw a profile. If you want to represent, something that
如果我想画一张描述图 如果你希望表示
has, this profile of great value and you actually want to discretize that.
这个表达灰度值的图 你需要对其离散化处理
If you do it very coarse, you're not going to be able to detect that there is
如果你画的很粗糙的话 你不会发现
a smooth variation in the gray values. But if on the other hand you are able to
这里灰度值有一个平滑的变化 但是如果另一方面
put many more layers, you're going to be able to capture its
你可以加入更多的层 你可以获取到
value at many, many points, instead of just at a few,
很多很多点的值 而不仅仅是很少的一些
let me just use a different color, just as a few values if you do a coarse
让我使用另一种颜色 只是几个通过粗略的离散化得到的值
discretization. And that's why this image doesn't look as
这也是为什么这图像看起来不像这张这么精细
nice as this one, because this capture what was going on at a very coarse levels
因为离散化是在一个很粗糙的层面上捕捉信息的
in the discretization, in the space discretization.
在空间上离散化
Now, similar things happen if you basically do a very coarse discretization
类似的 如果你对灰度值做一个粗糙的离散化
of the gray values. So let's just start,
我们再一次说好
and once again, we are not changing the number of pixels.
我们不改变像素的数量
All these four images and the four images that are going to come next have exactly
这四张图和接下来出现的四张图 像素个数完全相同
the same number of pixels. Okay? So actually, it's written here,
其实这里写了
it has 452, I'm going to just make it larger, times
它有452个像素 我把它写大一点
374, all the images.
乘以 374 所有的图都是
But, the first image is displayed with 8 bits, meaning 256 values.
但是第一张图使用了8 bits 表示 表示它可以有256个值
So I'm going to just write it, maybe I'm just going to say it here.
所以我把它们写下来 写在这里
The first is 256 and we actually see it very, very smooth and very, very nice.
第一张是256 我们可以看到它非常非常的平滑 非常非常精细
Here, we only use 7 bits or 128 values. So basically, the value 0 and 1 become 0,
这里 我们只使用了7 bits 或者说 128个值 基本来说 0和1被当做0
2 and 3 become 2, 4 and 5 become 4.
2和3被当做2 4和5被当做4
Okay? The easiest way to do that is you take
最简单的完成这件事的方法是
every value here, let's say a value, you divide by 2.
将这里的每一个值都除以 2
You take basically the closest integer from below and you multiply it again by
取比它们小的 最为接近它们的整数
2. Okay?
然后你再将它乘以2
So for example, if the value of this image was 8, you divide by 2,
这里比如说 如果这张图的这个值是8 除以2
you take, divide by 2, basic, divide. Sorry.
除以2 抱歉 写错了
Divide by 2, that's 4.
除以2 那就是4
Okay? You multiply by 2,
再乘以2
you got 8 again. No problem with that pixel value.
你又得到了8 对这个像素值没有影响
Okay? But what happen,
但是如果这样呢
let's just do that here, what happen if you have 9?
如果像素值为9 会发生什么？
You divide by 2, that's 4 and 1/2.
将它除以2 得到4又1/2
I have to take the closest integer from below,
我取比它小的 最为接近它的整数
that's 4, I multiplied by 2 and this became 8.
就是4 再将其乘以2 得到了8
So a 9 was transformed into an 8 and that's basically reduces the range and
这里9变化成了8 这样的操作减小了可取值的范围
reduces the quality of the image. This becomes even worse if we go into
同时也降低了图像的质量
this region where we are actually only using 64 different values.
在我们只使用64个不同值的情况下 可能更糟糕
So, that's equivalent basically to dividing by 4 then truncating and
这可以看成是 除以4 向下取整
multiplying by 4. And that means that you're going to start
然后再乘以4 这表示你将会
talking about basically, if you have only 64, every 4 values are represented with 1
如果你只有64个值 意味着每四个值由一个数字表示
number. So 0, 1, 2, 3, they all become 0.
这里 0、1、2、3全都变成了0
4, 5, 6, 7, they all become 4, and so on. And then, you can keep going and this is
4、5、6、7 全都变成了4 等等 你可以继续
only represented with 32. So I hope that you're starting to see
只用32个值来表示 我希望你会发现质量不断变差
that the quality is deteriorating. In particular, if you look at lines here,
特别的 如果你看看这里的线条
you start to see what's called false contours.
这是所谓的 伪轮廓
You see these lines that they're not clear here.
你可以看到这里的线条并不清晰
There is a smooth transition here, but here you see these false contours and
这里有一个平滑的过渡 但是这里你却能看到这些伪轮廓
that's created because of these jumps that I mentioned to you.
产生这个的原因就是因为刚才提到的那些被跳过的值
So if you were going basically 1, 2, 3, 4,
所以如果这里是 1、2、3、4
it's actually, you are going to, when you taking very, very few gray values, you're
事实上当你使用很少很少的灰度值的时候
going to go 0, 0, 0, 0, 4. You're going to jump into that value and
你得到的是0、0、0、4 你会得到那样的值
that's because you are basically have much less resources to represent the
因为你用了更少的资源来表示不同的灰度值
different gray values. It's just going into an even more extreme
这甚至会走向一个极端
case and we keep going down. Here, basically we used only 16 and now I
我们继续 这里我们只用16个值
think that you're going to be able to see the false countours very clearly.
相信你们可以清晰地看到 伪轮廓
Here, we go basically only to 8 values. There's only 8 numbers to represent
我们只使用 8个值 只用 8个数字来表示
everything that is happening in this picture.
图片中所展现的一切
Okay? And that's basically a very strong quantization.
这是一个很极端的量化过程
Here, there is basically only 4 and here is basically only 2.
这张图里只有4个值 这张里只有2个
In this very extreme case, everything that was below 128 became 0,
在这个极端的案例中 所有小于128的值都被设定为了0
became black. Everything that was above 128 became 255,
变成了黑色 所有大于128的值都设定为了255
white and then you see a very, very poor quality data.
变成了白色 然后得到了这组非常低质量的数据
Okay? So that's how the spatial quantization
这些就是空间量化
and the gray value, spatial sampling, sorry, and the gray value quantization
是空间采样 以及灰度值量化 是如何产生影响的
effect you. The more you have of samples, the better
当你有更多的样本的时候 你会得到更高的质量
quality it is, the more you have the possibility of represent many, many, many
对于灰度值 你有更多的可能显示更多的细节变化
small variations. In gray values, the better it is, of
图片质量也就越高 当然 这样则需要
course, the more memory it takes into your computer and that's going to be the
占用电脑中的越多的存储空间 这将在我们关于压缩的单元里学到
subject of our compression unit. So now we know how images are represented
现在我们知道了图片在电脑中是如何表示的
in the computer. They represent these two-dimensional
它们由这些二维数组表示
arrays. Great level images are represented by
灰度图像只用一个二维数组表示
one. Color images are represented by three,
彩色图像由三个数组表示 分别代表红、绿、蓝
red, green and blue. Videos are represented by multiples of
视频由很多图像表示
them, let's say 30 a second,
比如 每秒 30张
sometimes it's only 24 depending on the standard that, that we have,
有时候由于不同的标准 只有24张
but there are multiple of those images and as we say, we call them frames and we
总之就是有很多图像 就像我们前面说的 称它们为帧
know that everything is discrete. So we have something and quantization.
我们知道一切都是离散的 所以有采样和量化
An image in a computer is nothing else now that the two-dimensional array of
在计算机中 一张图片仅仅就是 元素为离散值的二维数组
discrete values. Thank you.
谢谢大家 //果壳教育无边界字幕组  Mosesdc | 神无月的鱼头 | 和风煦日 | 小白_远游